Graham Beer

311 Fair Oak Road, Bishopstoke, Eastleigh, SO50 8JU

Mobile: 07740 822 214 / Email: Graham.Beer@outlook.com LinkedIn: uk.linkedin.com/pub/graham-beer/51/789/7a1

Professional Profile

An experienced IT professional with over 18 years IT industry knowledge gained in Retail, Automotive Services and most recently in Education. A passionate and highly focused individual with an excellent wealth of knowledge in End User Services, Scripting, Systems Management and Automation, with excellent skills in PowerShell combined with SCCM (2012 & CB), PowerShell DSC, C#, Azure.

A keen technology enthusiast who dedicates time to continually learning about new and emerging areas of technology specifically DevOps Principals and Methodologies.

Confident to work using their own initiative, but equally comfortable working as part of a team. Easily adapts to new environments providing a driven, insightful and fresh perspective wherever they work.

Objective

Seeking opportunities to maximise usage of PowerShell skills to manage and automate solutions

Technical Skills

Languages: PowerShell, PowerShell DSC, SQL, C#, Git

Software: SCCM 2012, SCCM Current Branch, MDT, Office 365, Intune, Vagrant

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio 2015, Atom, GitHub, Chocolatey

Operating systems: Windows XP/7/8.1/10, Server 2003/2008/R2/2012/R2, Active Directory Currently developing skills in Cloud technologies, specifically Azure, C# and PowerShell DSC

Experience of writing SQL Reports

Good basic understanding of Networking concepts.

Career Highlights

- Upgraded SCCM 2012 R2 SP1 to SCCM Current Branch at The AA and Bournemouth University
- Full accountability for AA's PC software and hardware estate relating specifically the Mobile Patrols IT infrastructure
- Transitioned LANDesk 9.0 to SCCM 2012 R2 at the AA.
- Delivery of a desktop transformation project impacting over 10,000 machines, including creating Windows
 8.1 builds, Task Sequences, managing, planning and engineering SCCM management services
- Client Consultant responsible for managing and maintaining Desktop builds using LANDesk Management Suite for a £10million Desktop Modernisation Programme to roll out Windows 7 and 8/8.1 Desktops, Windows Embedded Thin clients and Windows 8.1 Tablets across more than 360 sites for over 25,000 users.
- Created own blog website https://graham-beer.github.io/ to communicate, enhance and share expertise in PowerShell Automation
- Had articles published on PowerShell.org, https://powershell.org/2016/08/11/a-date-with-powershell.org/to-ping-or-not-to-ping-the-powershell-way/

Career Summary

08/2016 - present SENIOR TECHNICAL CONSULTANT (contract) Bournemouth University

- Created customized reports utilizing SQL/SQL Reporting services to help assist on desktop inventory
- Creating Desired Configuration Management (DCM) baselines
- Design authority on best practices for SCCM 2012 including personal recommendations
- Automation zero-touch builds using PowerShell scripting.
- Scripted automation of BIOS changes for HP Desktops to meet Bournemouth University standards across all desktops
- Build creation for new Windows 10 images
- Upgrade of SCCM 2012 to SCCM Current Branch

10/2014 - 08/2016 SENIOR TECHNICAL CONSULTANT: DESKTOP The AA

- Lead Technical Administrator Microsoft SCCM 2012 R2 environment
- Creating and editing security groups, application deployments (collections, advertisements, task sequences, and PowerShell scripts), and delivering patch management, general troubleshooting, log

- analysis, and upgrade and recommendations on current infrastructure
- Providing technical expertise for a Windows 8.1 migration, package and application configuration/ deployment strategies, operating system deployment, and site hierarchy configuration settings
- Shell scripting with PowerShell for Windows systems
- Installing and configuring Windows Server 2012 for SCCM 2012 R2
- Contributing to operational changes such as upgrade from Office 2013 to Office 365
- Creating Windows 8.1 builds for multiple hardware types from MDT 2013, for a tactical Proof of Concept
- Administering Microsoft Intune for device management and delivery of applications and integration with SCCM 2012
- Production and compilation of management information, administering incident recording, tracking and documentation as part of Continuous Improvement.
- Working collaboratively with other AA IT functions and third parties to support end users and actively facilitate the highest possible levels of system availability

01/2014 - 10/2014 CLIENT CONSULTANT DESKTOP MODERNISATION PROJECT B&Q / Kingfisher PLC

- Managed and maintained Desktop builds using LANDesk Management Suite to facilitate £10million Desktop Modernisation Programme, and managed version control documentation across all PC builds
- Maintained Windows 7, 8 and 8.1 images with use of ImageX and DISM tools
- Created software packages, encompassing scripting with batch files and PowerShell; tested, scheduled and distributed packages using LANDesk Management Suite
- Used Bitlocker and Dell Data Protection software for Windows 8 Tablet device encryption
- Provided Endpoint Protection Policy management using LANDesk Security Management Suite
- Troubleshot hardware and software problems for OS platforms Windows 7, WES8 and Windows 8
- Administered site users and team documentation using SharePoint
- Provided regular, informed updates on testing and deployment to Project Managers

02/2007 - 01/2014 CLIENT INFRASTRUCTURE SERVICES SENIOR ANALYST B&Q / Kingfisher PLC

- Provided remote IT support including On-Call out-of-hours service for UK B&Q distributed estate, and managed ad-hoc software installation, machine rebuilds, and user queries and requests
- Installed software and applications to user standards, installed and configured peripherals, components and drivers, and configured and troubleshot desktops, laptops and server
- Managed incidents and service requests in the CIS Incident Queue through to successful resolution
- Supported client Windows OS's including Windows XP and Windows 7, and effectively leveraged sound knowledge of Windows Server 2003 and Windows Server 2008/R2
- Worked with Active Directory and Group Policy, including providing troubleshooting, and with network technologies LAN/WAN, VLAN's TCP/IP/DNS, WINS, DHCP and VPN, and Windows NAS/File systems, and system and data storage

06/2001 – 02/2007 SENIOR SUPPORT ANALYST / RETAIL APPLICATION SENIOR SUPPORT B&Q PLC

- 2nd Line IT support for UK B&Q stores' Windows and UNIX issues escalated from Service Desk,
- Team representative at meetings and Team Management in absence of Team Leader
- Installed and configured peripherals, components and drivers, hardware and software troubleshooting
- Tester on EPOS rollout project, including till image and Cash Office applications
- Provided Second Line support and managed all incidents and service requests in CIS Incident Queue through to resolution.

Education and Qualifications

Professional Training and Certifications:

- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS): Administering and Deploying System Center 2012 Configuration Manager
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (M10979)
- Administering System Center 2012 Configuration Manager (M10747)
- Windows 7, Enterprise Desktop Support Technician
- Bytes Fundamentals of Windows Server 2008
- LANDesk Training Course: Overview of fundamentals, patching, deployment and AV management
- Exchange 2007 Introduction to Installing and Managing
- > ITIL Course: Overview of widely-adopted approach to IT Service Management
- Advanced Information Technology and Intermediate Technology, GNVQ Level 3 Eastleigh College (1999)